we are going to generalize what we
talked about uh last time
uh which will be all about generalizing
and mathematically formalizing uh graph
neural networks
the idea for today's lecture is to
talk about deep graph encoders and
mathematically formalize them
and also show you the design space
the idea the diversity of what kind of
design choices
do we have when we are making these
types of
decisions uh building these types of
architectures
right so what we want is we want to
build a deep graph encoder that takes
the graph
as the input and then through a series
of non-linear
uh transformations uh through a kind of
this deep neural network
comes up with a set of uh predictions
that can be at node level
can be at the level of sub graphs pairs
of nodes um and so on
and what we talked about last time is
that the way we can define convolutional
neural networks on top of graphs
is to to think about the underlying
network
as the computation graph right so the
idea was when we discussed if i want to
make a prediction
for a given node in the network let's
say this red node i
then first i need to decide how to
compose a computation graph
based on the network neighborhood around
this node and then i can think of the
of the computation graph as the
structure of the graph neural of the
neural network
where now messages information gets
passed
uh and aggregated from a neighbor to
neighbor towards to the center node so
that the center node can make a
prediction
and we talked about how graph neural
networks allow us to learn
how to propagate and transform
information across the edges
of the underlying network to make a
prediction an embedding
at a given node so the intuition was
that nodes aggregate information from
their neighbors using neural networks
so we said that every node in the
network gets to define its own
multi-layer neural network structure
this neural network structure depends on
the neighbors
and the graph structure around the node
of interest so for example
node b here takes information from two
no two other nodes
uh a and c because they are neighbors of
it uh in the network
and then of course the goal will be to
learn um the transformations
in um in in this in this neural network
that that will be parameterized and this
way uh
our approach is going to work so the
intuition is that
network neighborhood defines a
computation graph and that every node
defines a computation graph
based on its network neighborhood so
every node in the graph
essentially can get its own neural
network architecture
because these are now different kind of
neural networks they have uh different
shapes
so now with this quick recap let's talk
about
how do we generally define graph neural
networks and
what are the components of them and how
do we mathematically formalize
these components so first in this
general framework is that we have two
aspects we have this notion of a message
and we have a notion of aggregation
and different architectures like gcn
graph sage
graph attention networks and so on and
so forth what they differ is how they
define this notion of aggregation
and how they define this notion of a
message
so that's the first important part is
how do we
define basically a single layer of a
graph neural network which compose
basically by taking the messages
uh from the children transforming them
and aggregating them so that's the
transformation and aggregation are the
first two core
operations the second set of
operations is about how are we stacking
together
multiple layers in a graph neural
network right so do we stack these
layers
sequentially do we add skip connections
and so on so that's the
that's the uh second part of the
equation is how do we add this
layer uh connectivity when i combine
layer one uh with layer two
um and then the the last part that uh
that
is an important design decision is how
do we
create the computation graph right do we
say that the the input graph
equals the computation graph or do we do
any kind of augmentation
maybe we want to do some feature
augmentation or we want to do some
graph structure manipulation again in
this lecture
i'm just kind of giving you an overview
of the areas where i will be going to
provide more detail and where we are
going
to go uh deeper so that's the that's the
the fourth area where
uh this becomes um where important
decide design decisions
uh have to be made and then the last
part is in terms of the learning
you know what kind of learn what kind of
objective function
what kind of tasks are we going to use
to learn the parameters of our graph
neural network right so how do we train
it do we train it in a supervised
unsupervised objective do we do it at
the level of
node prediction edge prediction or
entire graph
uh level uh prediction tasks so these
are essentially now gave you kind of an
overview
of the parts uh of the design design
space
uh for neural net graph neural network
architectures
so as i said first is defining the
layer then it's defining connectivity
between layers
it's about layer connectivity
it's about graph manipulation
augmentation feature augmentation
as well as finally the learning
objectives so these are the five
pieces we are going to talk about